Preliminary Guide to the Will Inman Papers, 1910-2003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accessions (1998-0395) and (1998-0404)
  - Correspondence, 1950s-1980s (Box 1)
    - Sitaramayya, K.B. (Box 2)
    - Smith, James (Box 2)
    - Smoot, Paul (Box 2)
    - Spoor, Dale (Box 2)
    - Srinivas, Krishna (Box 2)
    - Standish, Jim (Box 2)
    - St. Marks (Box 2)
    - Stanley, Will (Box 2)
    - Stanton, Robert (Box 2)
    - Starbuck, Jeff (Box 3)
    - Stelzig, Eugene (Box 3)
    - Stepleton, Jim (Box 3)
    - Stetler, Russell (Box 3)
    - Stewart, David (Box 3)
    - Stone, I.F. [ Ethan Stone] (Box 3)
    - Studies on Will Inman (Box 3)
    - Susshoetz, Michael (Box 3)
    - Sussman, Vic (Box 3)
    - Swallow, Alan (Box 3)
    - Swensen, Karen (Box 3)
    - Swift, Beulah (Box 3)
    - Tagliabue, John (Box 3)
    - Tagore Society (Box 3)
    - Tanner, Powell (Box 3)
    - Targets (Box 3)
    - Taylor, Bill (Box 3)
    - Terialles, Vincent (Box 3)
    - Terzian, Larry (Box 3)
    - Teunis, William (Box 3)
    - Thomas, Neal (Box 3)
    - Tignor, Marian (Box 3)
    - Tompkins Square Press (Box 3)
    - Touchet, Francis (Box 3)
    - Trunzo, Russ (Box 3)
    - Tucker, Harry (Box 3)
    - Tyrka (Box 3)
    - Tyson, Brady (Box 3)
    - Umbra (Box 3)
    - United Peoples (Box 3)
    - Ussery, Harvey and Evelyn (Box 3)
    - Village Voice (Box 3)
    - Vining, Kay (Box 3)
    - Vira, Soma (Box 3)
    - Von Bretzel, Philip (Box 3)
    - Vrbovska, Anca (Box 3)
    - Wachtel, Joel (Box 3)
    - Wakowski, Dianne (Box 3)
    - Waller, Bill (Box 3)
    - Walser, Richard (Box 3)
    - WAMU- FM (Box 3)
    - War Resisters League (Box 3)
    - Warley, Elliot (Box 3)
    - WBAI-FM (Box 3)
    - Weitzner, Rénee (Box 3)
    - Weddings (Box 3)
    - Wellman, John (Box 3)
    - West, Don (Box 3)
    - Wheaton College (Box 3)
    - White, Bob (Box 3)
    - White, Grace (Box 3)
    - Wilkinson, Ned (Box 3)
    - Willard, Robert (Box 3)
    - Williams, Jonathan (Box 3)
    - Williams, Vincent B. (Box 3)
    - Wilson, May (Box 3)
    - Winchester, Kermit (Box 3)
    - Winston Salem (Box 3)
    - Women's Group (Box 3)
    - Wolfe, Thomas (Box 3)
    - Wood, John (Box 3)
    - Writers and Editors - War Tax Protest (Box 3)
    - Writers Exchange - Herb Vernon (Box 3)
    - Yale Club Library (Box 3)
    - Yglesias, Roberto (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1980s-1990s (Box 4)
    Later correspondence, primarily with friends and other poets, arranged in alphabetical order. In almost all cases, Inman has included copies of his responses to the correspondence he received.
    - Bagby, Jeanne (Box 4)
    - Cage, Taylor (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Constable, Pam and Arturo Venezuela (Box 4)
    - Craven, Jerry (Box 4)
    - del Vecchio, Gloria (Box 4)
    - Falleder, Arnold (Box 4)
    - Fenton, Sharon (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - French, Elizabeth (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Gholsen, Christien (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Gove, Jim (5 folders) (Box 4)
    - Grumman, Bob (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Hanni, Carl (Box 5)
    - Huffstickler, Albert (9 folders) (Box 5)
    - Ingalls, Jeremy (Box 5)
    - Leber, Eric (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Luce, Ralph (Box 5)
    - Mariah, Paul (Box 5)
    - McAnally, Mary (Box 6)
    - Moore, Bob (Box 6)
    - Phillips, Milton (Box 6)
    - Robson, William (Box 6)
    - Rutowski, Thad (Box 6)
    - Sullivan, Kevin Patrick (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Taylor, Valerie (Box 6)
    - Thorn, Lee (Box 6)
    - Woods, Christopher (3 folders) (Box 6)
    - Yamrus, John (Box 6)
  - Writings (2 folders) (Box 6)
    Miscellaneous unsorted manuscripts, notes, fragments, and related clippings.
  - Clippings (2 folders) (Box 6)
    Primarily clippings of Conchsound in the Hills, Inman's newspaper column from the early 1970s.
  - Miscellaneous (3 folders) (Box 6)
    Assorted clippings, personal documents, and unsorted correspondence.
- Accessions (1998-0414) and (1998-0415)
  Accessions received in September of 1998 and minimally processed. These additions to the collection consist of correspondence with prisoners, correspondence with family members and other individuals, miscellaneous writings and notes, and published literary journals, magazines, and poetry anthologies.
  - Miscellaneous (2 folders) (Box 1)
    Miscellaneous unsorted notes, writings, and papers.
  - Correspondence with prisoners, 1975-1998
    Inman's correspondence with the prisoners began in the mid 1970s,when Inman first started teaching a writing workshop in several prisons near Tucson, and continued through to 1998.The letters themselves contain many examples of the writings that the prisoners produced during and after Inman's workshop and provide insights into the intense and supportive relationships that Inman developed with the prisoners. While this portion of the collection is open for research, those using it may not quote the names of individual prisoners. This correspondence has been arranged chronologically to the year level, but may need further processing before use.
    - Letters, 1975-1977 (1 folder) (Box 1)
    - Letters, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Letters, 1979 (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Letters, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Letters, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Letters, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Letters, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Letters; 1984 (Box 1)
    - Letters, 1985 (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Letters, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Letters, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Letters, 1989 (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Letters, miscellaneous 1990s (Box 1)
    - Letters, 1990 (1 folders) (Box 1)
    - Letters, 1990 (1 folders) (Box 2)
    - Letters, 1991 (5 folders) (Box 2)
    - Letters, 1992 (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Letters, 1993 (4 folders) (Box 2)
    - Letters, 1994 (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Letters, 1995 (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Letters, 1996 (2 folder) (Box 3)
    - Letters, 1997 (Box 3)
    - Letters, 1998 (Box 3)
    - Letters, undated (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, general
    - McGirt, William A., Sr. (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - McGirt, Harry G. (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Brigham, Besmilr (Box 3)
    - Giancola, Dan (Box 3)
    - Hill, Walter (Box 3)
    - Napora, Joe (6 folders) (Box 3)
    - Thorne, Evelyn (2 folder) (Box 3)
    - Tisdale, Walter (Box 3)
    - Tritica, John (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Published Materials (Box 4)
    Poetry journals, anthologies, and literary magazines, many featuring Inman's poetry and prose writings.
- Accessions (1998-0418) and (1998-0438)
  Accessions received in September 1998 and minimally processed. These accessions consist of small amounts of clippings from gay newspapers and literary journals and correspondence with editors and publishers of literary journals where Inman submitted work.
  - Correspondence with Editors, 1960s-1995 (Box 1)
    Inman's correspondence with editors and publishers of small literary journals spans 1966-1996 (bulk 1980-1995), and is chiefly concerned with the publication of his work. The letters of several editors who Inman corresponded with on a regular basis are arranged alphabetically by correspondent at the front of the collection. The bulk of the material, Inman's correspondence with miscellaneous editors, is arranged chronologically by the year.
    - Boyd, Greg, "Asylum Arts" (Box 1)
    - Chorlton, David and Roberta, The Signal (16 folders) (Box 1)
      Includes some correspondence with Joan Silva, co-editor of The Signal.
    - Daggy, Robert, " Thomas Merton Studies Center" (Box 1)
    - Dame, Enid, Home Planet News (Box 1)
    - De Frates, Steven, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - De Frates, Steven, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Hathaway, Michael, Chiron Review (Box 2)
    - Katz, Menke, "Bitterroot" (Box 2)
    - Kopelke, Kendra, "Passager" (Box 2)
    - Moe, Frederick, "Color Wheel" (Box 2)
    - Morse, Carl, Open Lines: Gay and Lesbian Poetry in Our Time (Box 2)
    - Packard, William, New York Quarterly (Box 2)
    - Page, Carolyn, Potato Eyes (Box 2)
    - Rogers, Norma, "Cultural Dimensions" (Box 2)
    - Stephenson, Shelby, "Pembroke Magazine" (Box 2)
    - Stone, Ken, Thirteen M.A.F. Press (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous Editors, 1960s (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous Editors, 1970s (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous Editors, 1980 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous Editors, 1981 (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous Editors, 1982 (Box 2)
- Accession (1998-0481)
  Accession received October, 1998.Includes copies of Inman's literary journal Kauri, other literary journals, and Inman's daily journal for 1995-1997.
  - Literary Journals (Box 1)
    - Kauri, 1964-1971 (6 folders) (Box 1)
    - Intrepid (Box 1)
  - Gargoyle (Box 1)
  - Writings
    - Miscellaneous (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1964 (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Works and Commentary, 1983-1986 (7 folders) (Box 1)
    - Poetry and Commentary, 1990 (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Journals, 1995-1997 (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Accession (1998-0534)
  Nine-box unprocessed accession received in December, 1998.Chiefly correspondence from the 1970s, poetry (1986), and literary magazines and pamphlets from the 1980sand 1990s.
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Correspondence (Box 5)
  - Correspondence (Box 6)
  - Correspondence (Box 7)
  - Writings (Box 7)
  - Poetry, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence (Box 8)
  - Literary Magazines (Box 8)
    Various literary magazines and poetry journals, chiefly from the 1980sand 1990s.
  - Literary Magazines (Box 9)
- Accession (1999-0030)
  Materials range in dates from 1938 through 1998
  - Correspondence, 1970s-1990s (unsorted) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1970s-1990s (unsorted) (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1970s-1990s (unsorted) (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1970s-1990s (unsorted) (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1970s-1990s (unsorted) (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1970s-1990s (unsorted) (Box 6)
  - Clippings, 1960s (Box 7)
  - Personal and Financial Papers (Box 7)
  - Diary, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Poetry, 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - Typescripts, ca.1950 (Box 8)
  - Typescripts, 1980s-1990s (Box 8)
  - School Yearbooks, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
  - Journals, 1990s (Box 8)
- Accession (1999-0156)
  One box unprocessed accession, chiefly correspondence, 1960s-1980s. Correspondents include Eugene Feldman, Robert Faber and Brother William McGrath.
  - William McGrath (Box 1)
  - Robert Feldman (Box 1)
  - Robert Faber (Box 1)
- Accession (1999-0192)
  Two boxes unprocessed correspondence and writings.
  - Randall, Margaret (Box 1)
  - Wise, Greg (Box 1)
  - Taylor, Charles (Box 1)
  - Allen, Chude (Box 1)
  - Whitebread, J. (Box 1)
  - Unsorted (8 folders) (Box 1)
  - Writings and miscellaneous printed materials (Box 2)
  - Baby book, 1923 (Box 2)
- Accession (1999-0258)
  Materials date: 1941-1994 (bulk 1966-1977)
  - Writings (5 folders) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Photographs, slides, and negatives (Box 1)
  - Printed Materials (7 folders) (Box 1)
    Includes clippings, newsletters, and journals
  - Printed Materials (6 folders) (Box 2)
    Primarily clippings of his column Conchsound in the Hills
  - Oversize Materials (Box 3)
    - Clippings (Box 3)
    - Volumes:
      - The Best of Ralph Waldo Emerson (Box 3)
      - Walden, with Inman's marginalia (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook (Box 4)
    All materials in this box arrived together pasted to a poster-size pad of paper, essentially used as a scrapbook. Includes clippings, letters, and other miscellaneous materials.
- Accession (2001-0195)
  Some of the materials in this collection are restricted: The correspondence may not be published.
  - Typescript poetry, 1997-2000; Journal/Diary (includes glued-in weather reports from the Tucson Citizen for each day), 2000 January 1- 2001 August 9; Correspondence/Poetry, 1976-1996 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1996; Paperback poetry journal, La Confluencia, 1978 March; Typescript poetry by Jimmy Santiago Baca, ca. 1977 and 1988 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1995; Typescripts of Inman's and Baca's poetry, 1977-1996 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence and Poetry, 1977-1980; A Resonance of Begetting, typed manuscript by Inman, 1999 January 8-9; Typescript poetry by Baca; Correspondence 1977-1978; Healing Earthquakes, by Baca, undated (Box 4)
  - Oversized material
    - Typescript poetry by Inman as Bill McGirt, 1940-1956, and as Inman, 1953-1957; Framed thank-you regarding the magazine Kauri to Inman from Louie Roddewig containing a poem, a hand-written note, and a two-dollar bill, undated (Box 5)
- Accession (2002-0143)
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - Correspondence (A-D) (Box 1)
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - Correspondence (D-I) (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (I-K) (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (K-M) (Box 4)
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (M-R) (Box 5)
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (R-W) (Box 6)
- Accessions (2003-0181) and (2003-0124)
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - [Loose Materials of Poetry and Prose Primarily by Inman.] 1957-2003 (Box 1)
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - [Loose Materials of Poetry and Prose Primarily by Inman.] 1957-2003 (Box 2)
    - [Loose Materials of Literary Periodicals and Collections of Poetry and Prose.] 1957-2003 (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - [Loose Materials of Poetry and Prose Primarily by Inman.] 1957-2003 (Box 3)
    - [Loose Materials of Literary Periodicals and Collections of Poetry and Prose.] 1957-2003 (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - [Loose Materials of Literary Periodicals and Collections of Poetry and Prose.] 1957-2003 (Box 4)
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - [Loose Materials of Literary Periodicals and Collections of Poetry and Prose.] 1957-2003 (Box 5)
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - [Loose Materials of Literary Periodicals and Collections of Poetry and Prose.] 1957-2003 (Box 6)
    - [Loose Materials of Poetry and Prose by Inman.] 1957-2003 (Box 6)
  - Contents of Box 7: (Box 7)
    - [Poetry and Prose Primarily by Inman.] 1957-2003 (Box 7)
  - Contents of Box 8: (Box 8)
    - [Poetry and Prose Primarily by Inman.] 1957-2003 (Box 8)
    - Paperweight (Box 8)
- Accession (2009-0263), 1976-2009, (1 box)
  Addition (09-263) (500 items, 0.6 lin. ft.; dated 1976-2009) includes correspondence, poetry by Inman and others, press releases and reviews, official documents (such as his birth certificate, insurance information, and medical documents), and materials from Inman's death and funeral.
  - General poetry, 2007-2009 (Box 1)
  - Poetry by Inman (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1976-2009 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Press releases and reviews (Box 1)
  - Newspaper articles, 2005-2007 (Box 1)
  - Official documents (legal and insurance materials) (Box 1)
  - Poets (Box 1)
  - Sierra Rx (Box 1)
  - Vam Tran (Box 1)
  - The Waterways Project (Box 1)
  - Home Planet News (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
  - Devon Gables Health Care Center, 2009 (Box 1)
  - Inman's death and funeral, 2009 (Box 1)
  - Cigar box with stamp collection and ephemera (Box 1)